# CORINA FLORESCU

University of North Texas, Denton, Texas  $(+1)682-429-6123 \diamond CorinaFlorescu@my.unt.edu$ 

### **SUMMARY**

Research scientist with 4+ years of academic experience. I work in an area between machine learning, natural language processing and text-mining. My research concerns the development of new methods to identify short phrases in the text of a document such that those phrases best capture the topics of the target document. I have developed several methods which benefits the indexing in scholarly. I am well connected in the academic community and have been presenting my work/tutorials to various natural language processing and data mining conferences.

### **EDUCATION**

# Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

January 2015 - Present

University of North Texas, Denton, Texas

### Master of Science, Databases

2008 - 2010

University of Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania

### Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Mathematics

2004 - 2008

University of Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania

## TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages
Software & Tools

Python, Java, LaTeX, C++, MySQL, MATLAB

TensorFlow, Keras, Weka, Hadoop

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Research Assistant

January 2015 - Present

 ${\it University~of~North~Texas,~Denton,~Texas}$ 

- · Developed keyphrase extraction systems for extracting keyphrases from scholarly documents; This extraction task aids indexing of documents in digital libraries, and hence, leads to improved organization, search, retrieval, and recommendation of scientific documents.
- · Developed a feature learning framework for automatically discover patterns that keyphrases express.
- · Developed a domain-independent supervised keyphrase extraction systems based on the learned representations.
- · Developed a ranking model to keyphrase extraction, such that the model can rank keyphrases according to their degree of representing the topic of a target document.

#### Computer Science Teacher

January 2015 - April 2015

I. L. Caragiale High School, Bucharest, Romania.

- · Worked in a team of six people and came up with a model of Dragon with movable wings
- · Taught programming languages (C++, SQL, PL/SQL, PHP)
- · Designed lecture plans
- · Evaluated students performance

### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Wei Jin, Corina Florescu. Improving Search and Retrieval in Digital Libraries by Leveraging Keyphrase Extraction Systems. In: Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Digital Libraries (JCDL 2018).

Corina Florescu, Wei Jin. Learning Feature Representations for Keyphrase Extraction. In: Proceedings of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2018).

Corina Florescu, Cornelia Caragea. PositionRank: An Unsupervised Approach to Keyphrase Extraction from Scholarly Documents. In: Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2017).

Corina Florescu, Cornelia Caragea. A Position-Biased PageRank Algorithm for Keyphrase Extraction. In: Proceedings of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2017).

#### FELLOWSHIPS & GRANTS

Scholarship from American Association for Artificial Intelligence

Travel Grant from Women in Machine Learning

Toulouse Graduate School(TGS) Tuition Benefit Scholarship

### ACADEMIC SERVICE

Manuscript peer review, Natural Language Engineering Journal

Manuscript peer review, Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data

Manuscript peer review, Language Resources and Evaluation

### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)